SALONI GARG

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

◆ NOIDA, INDIA

◆ 7217679493

• DETAILS •

Noida India 7217679493 salonig790@gmail.com

o SKILLS o

Java

Android

Kotlin

Mvvm

Analytical and Problem-Solving skills

System Design

Android SDK

Firebase

Data Structures and Algorithms

Git

Design Patterns

PROFILE

Android developer with 4 years of working experience developing android applications in travel, e-commerce, recharge and payments domains. Skilled in Android SDK, Kotlin, MVVM architecture, Android architecture components, Android Jetpack, Android webview, Material Design. Every day I learn new stuff to be on top of Android technologies and best practices. Enthusiastic about taking challenges and solving complex problems.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Senior Software Engineer(Android) at Paytm, Noida

July 2020 — Present

Paytm Mini Apps

- Developed custom andorid SDK for Payment Mini Apps, which is used to run multiple apps for merchants as well as internal components inside Paytm.
- Developed android SDK using Kotlin, MVVM architecture, Retrofit, constraint layout, Android webview.
- Developed features like logout, email population, QR code scan api for external merchants, domain access control to provide security while browsing mini app.
- Worked on scoped storage feature for paytm mini apps along with performance improvements.
- Handle release independently along with PR reviews.

Software Engineer(Android) at GlobalLogic, Noida

June 2019 — June 2020

Kohl's App

- Developed some featured of US based E-Commerce application. Worked on wallet screen of the app to show ollers and Gift cards.
- Worked on Product Details Screen by creating separate UI components as custom views like carousel, breadcrumbs, bottom sheet etc.
- Developed every feature using KOTLIN, ANDROID MVVM Architecture and JETPACK library with kotlin coroutines and retrolt.

Software Engineer(Android) at Tek Travels Pvt Ltd., Gurgaon

June 2017 — May 2019

TBO Holidays DMC APP

- Developed app from Scratch using MVVM architecture and Android Jetpack.
- Integrated Firebase for push notilications.

Roamer App

- Travel based app which acts as E-Travel pocketbook by showing travel bookings and creating an itinerary. Integrated Google Analytics/Firebase inside app.
- Implemented hotel image gallery feature and weather forecast feature.
- Developed features of the app using JAVA, Android Architecture components and material design.

EDUCATION

9 B.Tech Computer Science, Indraprastha College for Women, University of Delhi, Delhi July 2013 — May 2017